Privacy Policy
==============

Can’t find an answer for your question? [Contact us](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) 

Privacy Policy
==============

What information do we collect?
-------------------------------

We collect information from you when you register on our website, place an order, create user content or subscribe to our newsletter.

### Information provided by you:

* Name, email, profile picture - When you register for ProWritingAid we will ask for your email. Through your profile settings you may additionally provide a user name and profile picture. If you login using a social network (Facebook, LinkedIn or Bitbucket), we may ask permission to access basic information from that account, such as your name, email address and profile picture. You can stop sharing information with us at any time using the social network settings to disable access.
* Payment information (Paid Users) - Payment information is required to fulfil the transaction. If you pay using a payment card at checkout, you will provide your payment card number to Stripe® (our card payment provider). The Stripe® privacy policy will apply to this information. If you checkout using PayPal®, the PayPal® privacy policy will apply to the payment information you provide.
* User Content - This includes documents or any other content provided by you while using our website or apps.

### Information automatically collected:

* IP Address - For determining the location of the customer – place of supply – as required by European Union (EU) VAT B2C rules on broadcasting, telecommunications and e-services.
* Logging - It is very common for websites to record diagnostic data in log files. This log data may include the IP address, date, time, browser information and cookie data.
* Website Usage - To help understand and improve the performance of our service, we collect statistics such as how many users visit a page on our website or how many times a link was clicked.
* Cookies - We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. Please see our [cookie policy](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/CookiePolicy).

What do we use your information for?
------------------------------------

* To authenticate users, personalize your experience, improve customer service and process transactions.
* To communicate with you about your use of our website or apps, product announcements, software updates, as well as respond to your requests for support.
* To send periodic emails including direct marketing and special offers about ProWritingAid, from which you can unsubscribe at any time. EU users: We will only send you marketing emails with your prior consent.

Do we review your content?
--------------------------

We never use or access your content unless you specifically permit us to or where it’s required in order to comply with the law. For grammar checking, once checking has been completed, all submitted texts and their improvements will be deleted. When using ProWritingAid, your texts will not be used to improve the quality of our services. Beware: other providers do not take this approach, and you may granting them rights to use your content as they wish. We use texts hand corrected by professional copyeditors to train our algorithms to ensure that our data is of the highest quality.

You retain ownership of all content you post, upload to, or otherwise share on the site.

We do not retain any rights to any of the documents or other content uploaded into our system.

Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
--------------------------------------------------

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. The only exceptions to this rule are:

* Third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.
* When we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.
* Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

Do we use cookies?
------------------

Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information).  
We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

Will we send you emails?
------------------------

Periodically we may send you emails about new features and special offers. This may include information about product and services from our business partners. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found in our emails or by changing your [account settings](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Account/Manage).

> EU users: We will only send you marketing emails with your prior consent.

Do we collect information from children?
----------------------------------------

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. If we believe that personal information has been collected from a child younger than 13 years of age, we will remove it.

> Please do not submit any personal information through our website or apps if you are under the age of 13.

Where is my Information stored?
-------------------------------

Information that you transfer to our website and apps is processed and stored in the United States. If you transfer any Information to our website or apps, you agree to it being hosted and accessed in the United States.

How secure is my Information?
-----------------------------

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers’ database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems and are required to keep the information confidential.  
During and after a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) are not stored on our servers (except the last 4 digits).  
If we detect a system security breach, we may attempt to contact you using your email address.

How can I delete my data?
-------------------------

You can delete your data at any time by accessing the [account settings](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Account/Manage) on our website and clicking the “Delete Account” button.

How long is my data retained?
-----------------------------

We may keep some of your data for as long as it is required to comply with our obligations including law, tax and auditing.

California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
---------------------------------------------------

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent. As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at anytime by logging and clicking on their user name and then 'Edit your user details' page.

Users in the EU
---------------

We process, use and store personal data including those specified in the “What information do we collect?” section, as required to provide our services. We require your consent to process your personal data, send marketing emails.

What are my rights?
-------------------

Users in the EU have certain rights about their personal data including the right to access, correct or delete data we process through the use of our website or apps, you can:

* Request a report of the personal data by using our [contact](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) page
* Correct or delete your personal data using from our [account settings](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Account/Manage) page. If you have any problems with this let us know via the [contact](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) page.
* Object to the processing your personal data. You can request that we stop processing your personal data (including to send marketing emails). Marketing emails are only sent to users in the EU if we have consent to do so. You can unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link found in our emails or by changing your [account settings](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Account/Manage).
* Complain to your supervisory authority. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority of your country or EU member state about ProWritingAid’s use of your personal data.

For any questions regarding this please [contact](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) us.

Online Privacy Policy Only
--------------------------

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

Your Consent
------------

By using our site, you consent to our [privacy policy](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Privacy).

Changes to our privacy policy?
------------------------------

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.  

This document was last modified on 20-Feb-2024

Contact us
----------

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may use our [contact](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) page or in writing to:  
International House  
36-38 Cornhill  
London EC3V 3NG  
United Kingdom

EU Representative
-----------------

Chris Banks has been appointed as ProWritingAid's representative in the EEA for data protection matters, pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. Chris Banks can be contacted in matters related to the processing of Personal Data. To make such an inquiry, please contact Chris Banks using this contact form: [contact](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact).

Alternatively, Chris Banks can be contacted at:  
Calle Antoni Maria Alcover 42  
Palma de Mallorca  
07013  
Islas Baleares  
España

Features

Learn More

Company

Contact Us

[Drop us a line](https://prowritingaid.com/en/Home/Contact) or let's stay in touch via :

© 2024 - Orpheus Technology, prowritingaid.com
